A Guide to the Richard Harding Davis Papers, 1861-1915
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Richard Harding Davis Papers, 1861-1915
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6109 through 6109-e
This collection consists of approximately 250 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited in the Library by Clifton Waller Barrett 1959 December 30 (#6109); 1959 December 31 (#6109-a), 1960 April 16 (#6109-c); 1963 February 25 (#6109-d); and, 1963 July 16 (#6109-e). The entire collection was converted to a gift 1991 July 1.
Scope and Content Information
The collection consists of correspondence; pieces from the diary (1865-1879) of Davis' mother, Rebecca Harding Davis; MSS of Davis' plays and dramatizations by others from Davis' stories; agreements between Davis and various publishers; copyrights; clippings concerning Davis' father's death in 1904; notebooks, address books, accounts, notes; Lehigh College scrapbook (1880-1884), photographs, and other papers. Includes draft of article on Joseph Pulitzer, notes on the life of Philo Norton McGiffen, preface to an unpublished story on South America, correspondence, clippings, tracts, etc. (1907-1909) relating to Sebastian H.L. de Magali's Brazil filibuster incident, and correspondence of Davis' father, Lemuel Clarke Davis, his brother, Charles Belmont Davis, and his mother, Rebecca Harding Davis.
Correspondents include Louisa May Alcott, Henry Mills Alden, Robert Bacon, James Gillespie Blaine, Edward William Bok, John Griffin Carlisle, Warwick Stevens Carpenter, Wilbur John Carr, Arthur W. Carswell, George William Childs, Grover Cleveland, Mr. and Mrs. William Collier, Edward Fales Coward, George William Curtis, Augustin Daly, Pierre Paul Demers, Mary Dillon, Irving Bedell Dudley, Bernard Morris Lee Ernst, Ernst & Cane, Adam Everly, John Fox, Jr., Charles Frohman, Daniel Frohman, F.E. Fyles, Franklin Fyles, Edward James Garner, Mr. and Mrs. Charles Dana Gibson, J. Henry Harper, Harper & Bros., O. Harrington, George Harvey, John Hay, Rutherford B. Hayes, Henry Hayns, Hilary Abner Herbert, Laura Hoffmann, Oliver Wendell Holmes, Carl Hovey, Henry Irving, Helen Jackson, Joseph Jefferson, William B.B. King, Frederick Leslie, Llewellyn Legge, Will H. Lewis, Jr., William Loeb, André de Lorde, Henry Ronald Douglass MacIver, Sebastien H.L. de Magali, John Hudson Merrill, Nelson Appleton Miles, Levi Parsons Morton, George Parker, Jr. and Sr., J.C. Pegram, Jr., Sir Arthur Wing Pinero, Henry Codman Potter, Thomas Brackett Reed, William Charles Reick, Paul Revere Reynolds, Elihu Root, Arthur Hawley Scribner, Charles Scribner, John Sherman, Harriet Beecher Stowe, Tarleton B. Taylor, Ellen Terry, Arthur Turner Vance, Frank H. Warner, Thomas Bucklin Wells, Francis Wilson, Huntington Wilson, and George E. Wood.
Contents List
- Letters
  - Rebecca Harding Davis to Mr. and Mrs. Fields 1861, 20 ALsS (Box 1)
  - Rebecca Harding Davis to Mr. and Mrs. Fields 1862, 36 ALsS (Box 1)
  - Rebecca Harding Davis to Mr. and Mrs. Fields 1863, 25 ALsS (Box 1)
  - Rebecca Harding Davis to Mr. and Mrs. Fields 1864, 11 ALsS (Box 1)
  - Rebecca Harding Davis to Mr. and Mrs. Fields 1865, 17 ALsS (Box 1)
  - Rebecca Harding Davis - parts of her diary 1865-1869, Ca. 64 pieces (Box 1)
  - Rebecca Harding Davis to Mr. and Mrs. Fields 1866, 5 ALsS (Box 1)
  - Rebecca Harding Davis to Mr. and Mrs. Fields 1867, 2 ALsS (Box 1)
  - Rebecca Harding Davis to Mr. and Mrs. Fields 1868-1869, 6 ALsS (Box 1)
  - Rebecca Harding Davis to Mr. and Mrs. Fields 1870, 2 ALsS (Box 1)
  - Rebecca Harding Davis to Mr. and Mrs. Fields 1871, 9 ALsS (Box 1)
  - Rebecca Harding Davis to Mr. and Mrs. Fields 1879, 9 ALsS (Box 1)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1878, 2 ALsS (Box 1)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family [1878-1880], 12 ALsS (Box 1)
  - Richard Harding Davis to members of his family ante 1880, 6 ALsS, 2 APCS (Box 1)
  - Richard Harding Davis to members of his family, most contain illustrations 1880, 15 ALsS. (Box 1)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Gus [Williams] 1880, ALS (Box 1)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family [1880-1886], 19 ALsS (Box 1)
  - Richard Harding Davis to members of his family 1881-1882, 23 ALsS, 2 APCS (Box 1)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family [1883-1886], 23 APCS (Box 1)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1885-1886, 72 ALS, 3 APCS (Box 1)
  - Richard Harding Davis to "Aunt Cuddy" 1887, ALS (Box 2)
  - Richard Harding Davis to members of his family 1888, 8 ALsS (Box 2)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1889, 28 ALsS (Box 2)
  - Richard Harding Davis to his mother [1889-1896], 7 ALsS (Box 2)
  - Richard Harding Davis to members of his family 1890, 10 ALsS (Box 2)
  - Richard Harding Davis to members of his family 1890, n.d., 35 ALsS (Box 2)
  - Richard Harding Davis to members of his family, with ten clippings 1891, 27 ALsS (Box 2)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Gus [Williams] 1891, 2 ALsS (Box 2)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1892 Jan-May, 14 ALsS. Telegram. (Box 2)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1892 Jun-n.d., 16 ALsS, ANS (Box 2)
  - Richard Harding Davis to his mother 1893 Jan-Mar, 14 ALsS, Telegram (Box 3)
  - Richard Harding Davis to his mother 1893 Apr-Dec, 21 ALsS, Telegram (Box 3)
  - Richard Harding Davis to members of his family 1894 Jan-Jun, 16 ALsS (Box 3)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family, with poems 1894 Jul-n.d., 12 ALsS, Telegram (Box 3)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1895 Jan-Mar, 13 ALsS (Box 3)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1895 Apr-n.d., 15 ALsS (Box 3)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1896 Feb-Nov, 16 ALsS, Telegram (Box 3)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1896 Dec-n.d., 15 ALsS. 2 Telegrams. (Box 3)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family, with four clippings 1897, 36 ALsS, Telegram (Box 4)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family, with two clippings 1897, 20 ALsS (Box 4)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1898 Jan-May, 16 ALsS. 3 Telegrams. (Box 4)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1898 June-n.d., 22 ALsS (Box 4)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1899 Feb-Dec, 23 ALsS (Box 4)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1899-n.d., 21 ALsS (Box 4)
  - Richard Harding Davis to his mother [1899-1900], 8 ALsS, APCS (Box 4)
  - Richard Harding Davis to his mother [1899-1904], 25 ALsS (Box 4)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1900, 8 ALsS, Cable (Box 5)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1901, 4 ALsS, Telegram (Box 5)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1902, 20 ALsS, 2 Telegrams (Box 5)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1903 Jan-May, 27 ALsS, Telegram (Box 5)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1903 Jul-Dec, 26 ALsS (Box 5)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1903-n.d., 80 ALsS (Box 5)
  - Richard Harding Davis to his mother [1903-1906], 39 ALsS (Box 5)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1904 Jan-Jun, 36 ALsS (Box 5)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1904 Jul-Dec, 35 ALsS (Box 5)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1904-n.d., 56 ALsS (Box 5)
  - Charles Frohman to Richard Harding Davis 1904, 3 TLsS (Box 5)
  - Rebecca Harding Davis to Richard Harding Davis 1904-1908, 54 ALsS (Box 6)
  - Letters to Richard Harding Davis concerning the death of his father, Lemuel Clark Davis 1904, 19 ALsS, Telegram (Box 6)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1905 Jan-Dec, 49 ALsS. With one clipping. (Box 6)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1905-n.d., 52 ALsS, APCS (Box 6)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1906 Jan-Dec, 18 ALsS (Box 7)
  - Mrs. H. Ingram to Richard Harding Davis 1906, TLS. (Box 7)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1907 Jan-Dec, 30 ALsS, APCS. With one clipping Telegram. (Box 7)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1908 Jan-Jul, 38 ALsS. With one clipping. (Box 7)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1908 Aug-Dec, 23 ALsS (Box 7)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1908-n.d., 35 ALsS. With one clipping. (Box 7)
  - Richard Harding Davis to his mother [1908], 8 ALsS. (Box 7)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1909 Jan-Jul, 24 ALsS (Box 7)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1909 Aug-Dec, 21 ALsS (Box 7)
  - Richard Harding Davis to his mother [190?], 9 ALsS. (Box 7)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1910, 8 ALsS (Box 8)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1911-1912, 3 ALsS (Box 8)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1913, 18 ALsS (Box 8)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1914, 26 ALsS (Box 8)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Family 1915 May-Dec, 11 ALsS, APCS. With clippings. (Box 8)
  - New York Conservation Commission to Richard Harding Davis 1915, 4 TLsS, ANS (Box 8)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Charles Belmont Davis n.d., 103 ALsS (Box 9)
  - Richard Harding Davis to Charles Belmont Davis n.d., 69 ALsS & ANS (Box 9)
  - Richard Harding Davis to his mother and family n.d., 213 ALsS. 13 folders. (Box 9)
  - Addressed to Charles Belmont Davis n.d., 56 envelopes (Box 9)
    Most are not in Richard Harding Davis's hand
  - Lemuel Clarke Davis to James T. Fields and Annie Fields 1863-1873, 7 ALsS (Box 12)
  - James G. Blaine to Lemuel Clarke Davis 1880 Nov 9, ALS (Box 12)
  - Rutherford B. Hayes to Lemuel Clarke Davis 1880 Jan-Feb, 3 ALsS (Box 12)
  - Augustin Daly to Lemuel Clarke Davis 1886-1896, 12 ALsS (Box 12)
  - Joseph Jefferson to Lemuel Clarke Davis 1887, 8 ALsS (Box 12)
  - Frederick Leslie, G. W. Curtis, Thomas Reed, H. A. Herbert, and John Hay to Lemuel Clarke Davis 1889-1901, 8 ALsS and TLsS (Box 12)
  - Grover Cleveland to Lemuel Clarke Davis 1890-1902, 10 ALsS and TLsS (Box 12)
  - Richard Harding Davis' contracts and letters to publishers 1891-1918, 50 items (Box 12)
  - Letters of Richard Harding Davis, with manuscript fragments 1893-1916, 14 items (Box 12)
  - Contracts and letters re Henry MacIver 1902-1908, 13 items (Box 12)
  - Sebastian H. L. de Magali to Richard Harding Davis 1907, 9 ALsS and TLsS (Box 12)
  - Officials in the United States Department to Richard Harding Davis re Magali incident 1907-1909, 16 TLsS (Box 12)
  - Clippings re Magali incident 1907-1909, 38 items (Box 12)
  - George Parker and Samuel Parker to Richard Harding Davis re Magali incident 1908-1910, 6 items (Box 12)
  - Tracts by Sebastian H. L. de Magali ca. 1909, 7 AMss (Box 12)
- Manuscripts
  - "An Appeal," preface to an unpublished story re South America n.d., AMsS, 3 p. (Box 10)
  - Blackmail, a one-act play, with autograph corrections n.d., TMs, 27 p. (Box 10)
  - Blackmailer n.d., TMs, 24 p. [Blackmail], with carbon (Box 10)
  - Blackmailer [Blackmail], pages from n.d., TMs (carbon), 23 p. (Box 10)
  - Blood Will Tell, play n.d., AMs, 126 p. (Box 10)
  - The Boys in the Adirondacks n.d., AMs, 84 p. Barrett slipcase. (Box 10)
  - Captain Kidd, play, musical made from The Dictator, with carbons of six pages [1909], TMsS, 148 p. (Box 10)
  - The Dictator, play [1909], TMsS, 98 p. (Box 10)
  - "Dr. Jameson's Raiders," printed pamphlet, autographed 1897, Printed, 56 p. (Box 10)
  - The Frame-up, play, by Edward Cooke, from a story by Richard Harding Davis n.d., TMs (carbon), 14 p. (Box 10)
  - The Incorrigible Dukane, screenplay, by Russell E. Smith, from a story by Richard Harding Davis n.d., TMs, 40 p. (Box 10)
  - "Log of the Jolly Polly," story [1920], AMsS, 98 p. (Box 10)
  - Notes on the life of Philo Norton McGiffen n.d., AMs, 5 p. (Box 10)
  - Richard Harding Davis, play by Walter Casey and Vincent McConnor n.d., TMs (carbon). 187 p. (Box 10)
  - The System of Dr. Goudron and Professor Plume, play by André de Lourde, adapted by Richard Harding Davis n.d., TMs, 26 p. (Box 10)
  - Notes on Joseph Pulitzer [1911], AMs, 4 p. (Box 10)
  - The Taming of Helen, play [1902], TMsS, TMs. 102 p. (Box 11)
  - Vera the Medium, play by Howard Erwood, from the story by Richard Harding Davis n.d., TMs (carbon). 124 p. (Box 11)
  - Vera the Medium, play by Edward Cooke, from the story by Richard Harding Davis n.d., TMs (carbon). 68 p. (Box 11)
  - Yankee Tourist, play 1907, Printed, 161 p. (Box 11)
- Photographs
  - Henry MacIver, in various poses and uniforms, signed by MacIver 1902, 7 Photographs (Box 12)
- Miscellaneous
  - Includes twenty-two obituaries of Lemuel Clarke Davis 1863-1914, Clippings (Box 12)
  - Re the Rosslyn dispute 1900 Sep, Clippings (Box 12)
  - Re General Russell Alexander Alger 1901, Clippings (Box 12)
  - Announcement of Richard Harding Davis' election to the National Geographic Society 1906 May 17, Document (Box 12)
  - For the benefit sale for Belgian Sufferers 1915 May 20, Catalog (Box 12)
  - Accounts of Richard Harding Davis 1912-1915, 10 items (Box 12)
  - Officer's notebook, "War Manoeuvres" 1903, Bound volume (Box 13)
  - Field Service Regulations 1914, Booklet (Box 13)
  - Notebook re constitutional history of America and England n.d., Bound volume (Box 13)
  - Draft of charter for Military Order of Pretoria n.d., Draft (Box 13)
  - Address books belonging to Richard Harding Davis n.d., 3 Bound volumes (Box 13)
  - Notebooks re Military Order of Pretoria, Congo, Republican Convention of 1912, etc. 1905-1914, 7 Bound volumes (Box 13)
  - Photograph album re London and Brighton 1911, Bound volume (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook re Lehigh College belonging to Richard Harding Davis 1880-1884, Bound volume (Box 13)
  - "Miss Delmar's Understudy." 1896, AMsS, 62 pp., written in pencil on unlined paper (21 x 17.5 cm), red-lined paper (28.5 x 19.5 cm), and blue-lined paper (31 x 20 cm). (Box 13)
    #6109-c
  - Letter from Richard Harding Davis to La Touch Hancock December 19, ALS, 1 p. (Box 14)
    Also enclosed is a 1 p. AMS biographical note. #6109-d
  - Lithograph of Richard Harding Davis n.d., 17 x 11 cm (Box 14)
    Head and shoulders of Richard Harding Davis, by Penrhyn Stanlaws. #6109-d
  - Manuscript n.d., AMS, 1 p. (Box 14)
    Biographical outline of Richard Harding Davis in an unidentified hand. #6109-d
- Poem beginning, "And is there no sweet spell..." n.d., AMs, 3 pp. (Box 14)
  #6109-e
- Letters 1879-1917, n.d. (Box 14, 15)
  - Rutherford B. Hayes to Lemuel Clarke Davis June 5, 1879, ALS, 1 p. with envelope (Box 14)
  - Jefferson Davis to Col. A.K. McClure December 23, 1884, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - Oliver Wendell Holmes to George W[endell] Childs July 1, 1887, ALS, 2 pp. with envelope (Box 14)
  - Julia Marlowe to Richard Harding Davis April 10, 1891, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - Sir Henry Irving to Richard Harding Davis November 17, 1893, ANS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - George Curzon to Richard Harding Davis April 22, 1894, ALS, 4 pp. (Box 14)
  - Albert Chevalier to Richard Harding Davis March 21, 1895, ALS, 3 pp. (Box 14)
  - Ellen Terry to Richard Harding Davis December 25, 1895, ALS, 2 pp. with envelope (Box 14)
  - John Hay to Lemuel Clarke Davis November 26, 1896, ALS, 3 pp. with envelope (Box 14)
  - Sir Anthony Hope Hawkins to Richard Harding Davis January 25, 1897, ALS, 4 pp. (Box 14)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Richard Harding Davis December 16, 1898, ALS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Richmond Pearson Hobson to Richard Harding Davis July 6, 1899, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - Joseph Jefferson to Richard Harding Davis July 10, 1899, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - John Hay to Lemuel Clarke Davis August 11, 1900, ALS, 2 pp. with envelope (Box 14)
  - John Hay to Lemuel Clarke Davis November 30, 1900, TLS, 2 pp. with envelope (Box 14)
  - Winston Churchill to Richard Harding Davis December 17, 1900, ALS, 4 pp. (Box 14)
  - Corrie Reitz to Richard Harding Davis February 16, 1901, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - Arthur Pinero to Richard Harding Davis April 3, 1901, ALS, 3 pp. with envelope (Box 14)
  - Edward L[ivermore] Burlingame to Richard Harding Davis May 15, 1901, ALS, 3 pp. (Box 14)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Richard Harding Davis December 28, 1901, ANS, 1 p. with envelope, autograph postscript (Box 14)
  - Anthony Hope Hawkins to Richard Harding Davis June 29, 1902, ALS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Albert Chevalier to Richard Harding Davis October 7, 1902, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - [Francis William] Reitz to Richard Harding Davis November 8, 1902, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - Gordon A. Fraser to Richard Harding Davis November 14, 1902 (Box 14)
  - Owen Wister to Richard Harding Davis January 31, 1903, ALS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Richard Harding Davis February 11, 1903, TLS, 2 pp. with envelope (Box 14)
  - Augustus Thomas to Richard Harding Davis February 12, 1903, TLS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Elihu Root to Richard Harding Davis March 17, 1903, TLS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - George Dewey to Richard Harding Davis July 28, 1903, TLS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Lemuel Clarke Davis September 21, 1903, TLS, 2 pp. with envelope (Box 14)
  - Winston Churcill to Richard Harding Davis September 26, 1903, TLS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Lemuel Clarke Davis October 5, 1903, TLS, 8 pp. with envelope (Box 14)
  - John Hay to Richard Harding Davis November 13, 1903, TLS, 1 p. (Box 13)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Richard Harding Davis December 22, 1903, TLS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - [Elihu Root] to Richard Harding Davis December 26, 1903, TL (frag), 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Augustus Thomas to Richard Harding Davis January 2, 1904, TLS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Owen Wister to Richard Harding Davis January 9, 1904, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - Francis Wilson to Richard Harding Davis August 6, 1904, ALS, 3 pp. (Box 14)
  - Jack London to Richard Harding Davis August 10, 1994, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - Jack London to Richard Harding Davis December 27, 1904, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Richard Harding Davis January 3, 1905, TLS, 3 pp. with envelope (Box 14)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Richard Harding Davis [January 9, 1905], TNS, 1 p. with envelope (Box 14)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Richard Harding Davis May 13, 1905, TLS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
    with autograph note
  - Robert W. Chambers to Richard Harding Davis October 26, 1905, ALS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - William Travers Jerome to Richard Harding Davis November 16, 1905, TLS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Winston S. Churchill to Richard Harding Davis May 19, 1906, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
    Churchill agrees to send photographs for Real Soldiers of Fortune (1906) which included a biography of Churchill.
  - Jesse Lynch Williams to Richard Harding Davis May 31, 1906, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - Winston Churchill to Richard Harding Davis June 29, 1906, TLS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Winston Churchill to Richard Harding Davis September 4, 1906, TLS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Winston Churchill to Richard Harding Davis October 21, 1906, ALS, 3 pp. (Box 14)
  - Sir Gerald Du Maurier to Richard Harding Davis February 10, 1907, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 14)
  - Sir Gerald Du Maurier to Richard Harding Davis March 8, 1907, ALS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - [Gouverneur Morris] to Charles [Belmont Davis] August 6, 1907, AL (fragment), 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Winston S. Churchill to Richard Harding Davis September 20, 1907, ALS, 3 pp. (Box 14)
    Churchill excuses Davis from any "malicious motive" for including material in Real Soldiers of Fortune(1906) that was inaccurate, "possibly-- libelous."
  - Dorothy Stanley to Richard Harding Davis February 14, 1908, ALS, 4 pp. (Box 14)
  - Anthony Hope Hopkins to Richard Harding Davis January 4, 1909, ALS, 1 p. (Box 14)
  - Anthony Hope Hopkins to Richard Harding Davis January 22, 1909, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Anthony Hope Hawkins to Richard Harding Davis March 12, 1909, ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Anthony Hope Hawkins to Richard Harding Davis September 17, 1910, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Richard Harding Davis October 1, 1910, December 24, 1910 (Box 15)
  - Gouverneur Morris to Richard Harding Davis December 28, 1910, ALS, 4 pp. (Box 15)
  - Anthony Hope Hawkins to Richard Harding Davis June 14, 1911, ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Anthony Hope Hawkins to Richard Harding Davis August 25, 1911, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Leonard Wood to Richard Harding Davis February 1, 1913, TLS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Augustus Thomas to Richard Harding Davis July 11, 1913, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Elihu Root to Richard Harding Davis December 18, 1913, TLS (Box 15)
  - George Dewey to Richard Harding Davis December 27, 1913, TLS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Stephen Whitman to Richard Harding Davis Feburary 6, 1914, ALS, 3 pp. (Box 15)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Richard Harding Davis July 18, 1914, TLS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Winston Churchill to Richard Harding Davis October 31, 1914, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Jean Jules Jusserand to Richard Harding Davis November 4, 1914, TLS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
    With autographed calling card
  - Jean Jules Jusserand to Richard Harding Davis December 24, 1914, TLS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Richard Harding Davis December 29, 1914, TLS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Anthony Hope Hawkins to Richard Harding to Davis January 3, 1915, ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - J. Brigenbleek to Richard Harding Davis January 15, 1915, ALS, 1 p. with envelope (Box 15)
  - Arthur ("Hugh") Frazier to Richard Harding Davis January 15, 1915, ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - [Finley] Peter [Dunne] to Richard Harding Davis Feburary 3, 1915, ALS, 4 pp. (Box 15)
  - Authors' League to Richard Harding Davis February 13, 1915, TLS, 1 p. (Box 15)
    Signed by Hamlin Garland, Rex Beach, Harvey O'Higgens, and Ellis P. Butler.
  - J. Brigenbleek to Richard Harding Davis March 11, 1915, ALS, 1 p. with envelope (Box 15)
  - Arthur Wing Pinero to Richard Harding Davis June 11, 1915, ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - George Barr McCutcheon to Richard Harding Davis April 3, 1916, ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Cyril Maude to Richard Harding Davis [April 3, 1916], ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Charles Belmont Davis April 22, 1916, TLS, 1 p. with envelope (Box 15)
  - Augustus Thomas to Charles Belmont Davis June 5, 1916, TLS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Theodore Roosevelt to Charles Belmont Davis June 27, 1916, TLS, 1 p. with envelope (Box 15)
  - Herbert Bayard Swope to Elizabeth McEvoy Davis September 16, 1917, ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Rowland Thomas to [Richard Harding] Davis February 4, n.y., ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Charles Dana [Gibson] to [Richard Harding Davis] April 2, n.y., ALS, 3 pp. (Box 15)
  - Raymond Hitchcock to [Richard Harding] Davis June 11, n.y., ALS, 3 pp. (Box 15)
  - Paul Bourget to [Richard Harding] Davis June 15, n.y., ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Booth Tarkington to [Richard Harding] Davis June 24, n.y., ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - John Drew to [Richard Harding Davis] October 4, n.y., ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Booth Tarkington to [Richard Harding] Davis October 7, n.y., ALS, 4 pp. (Box 15)
  - Paul Bourget to [Richard Harding Davis] n.d., ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Arthur Wing Pinero to [_______], introducing Richard Harding Davis n.d., ANS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Maude Adams to Richard Harding Davis n.d., ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Anthony Hope Hawkins to Richard Harding Davis "Saturday", ALS, 3 pp. (Box 15)
  - [_________] to Richard Harding Davis "Thursday", ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Edward H. Sothern to Richard Harding Davis n.d., ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Edward. H. Sothern to Richard Harding Davis n.d., ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Irwin S[hrewsbury] Cobb to Richard Harding Davis "Tuesday", ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - [Francis William] Reitz to Richard Harding Davis n.d., ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Gouverneur Morris to Charles [Belmont Davis] n.d., ALS, 1p. (Box 15)
  - Gouverneur Morris to Richard Harding Davis n.d., ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Gouverneur Morris to Richard Harding Davis "Friday", ALS, 2 pp. (Box 15)
  - Gouverneur Morris to Richard Harding Davis n.d., ALS, 3 pp. (Box 15)
  - Gouverneur Morris to Richard Harding Davis n.d., ALS, 3pp. (Box 15)
  - Gouverneur Morris to Richard Harding Davis n.d., ALS, 3 pp. (Box 15)
  - A[lfred]; E[dward]; W[oodley] Mason to Mrs. Richard Harding Davis n.d., ANS, 1 p. (Box 15)
  - Winston Churchill to Richard Harding Davis n.d., ALS, 4 pp. (Box 15)
  - Ellen Terry to Richard Harding Davis "Monday", ALS, 3 pp. (Box 15)
  - George Ade to Richard Harding Davis "Wednesday", ALS, 1 p. (Box 15)